We want to have an invocation by our marchief, Mr. Robert Rutt.
Thank you.
Oh, I see you.
We pray, please.
Well, God, I thank you for this day, and I thank you for each version here.
I ask God that you will bless the decisions that are made,
and that will be your will.
I ask it to be with the Council of Mayer,
and their families put a hedge protection around them.
I ask God that you've walked over the city, and it's important to ease.
Thank you, again, for each version here.
It's a near-sense name, right?
I'm really proud.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America,
and to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation, another God, and it is with liberty and justice for all.
For public input, I'm scheduled to personal appearances.
Five, consent agenda.
Staff recommends we approve item six through 11.
Make a motion.
We approve.
Second.
Estep.
Aye.
Sumber.
Davis.
Aye.
The whole.
12.
Action on them.
Letter of engagement with Walden.
Financial services.
Perform at 22 electric water.
Waste water.
And saw the waste rate study.
And non-rate study.
Feast study.
So, at your seat is a revised.
It's forward.
And if you look at the VA, there's a very list of all the ranks.
And non-rate.
But there's more.
We're asking that their study is on that VA.
Non-rate would be things like animal control fees, all fuel rentals, just to power rentals,
things like that that aren't like a rate for electric water or sewer or sanitation.
But those are also included in this study.
The cost is $60,500.
We've used World Lands since 2000.
I have a very good relationship.
There are numbers that are spot on.
And it says that we feel very comfortable with their numbers that they provide us.
And they estimate what revenue would have of the rates.
Which is very important for the budget season.
The last time the Council enacted rates.
Well, actually the last time they went into effect.
Electric.
At an increased April 21.
More waste when it was October 20.
months that the last time in the sanitation was January of 19th, and many of these other
non-rights hadn't been looked at for a year or two years, something like that, and many
of them.
When did you say electric was in point on well?
The last time, the increased curve was April 21, so I just didn't know what to do.
So when they when Tiger brought the race to the results to the council, there was a plan
for the World of the Family of the Women's Revolution for the 10 years.
The council acted on a portion of that.
So now that things have changed dramatically since COVID, now we're looking at it as of today.
So long ago was the last one of these.
Well, what electric was?
It's in the BA 2017-19.
So do we feel like our rates are out of line with everyone else?
Or are we just doing this because we always do that?
It's making sure that they are in line.
And again, some of them have been studied some of the 10 years that I know for sure.
And then other electric water, wastewater, and sanitation was done some time before the electric water and wastewater.
But it was a larger plan than what was accepted by the council.
We were able to see the old one that the council accepted.
Absolutely.
Can you email them to all of this?
I think we'd all like to see them for that.
I think probably I could say, I don't want to speak for everyone but I think I can.
Are they?
our biggest concern is we're talking about raising rates on every, you know, it's me and
you remember, we didn't want to make sure we're doing this right, and make sure we're
all in agreement on what's going on, why we're doing it, and why it was before, and when
it was agreed on, and before we.
So this is for the state.
And then we have to bring the ordinance to you to actually increase the rate.
We completely agree.
That's why we're requesting, we do a completely new study to ensure that our numbers are
accurate, which will then, that would, the outcome of this would be going to play in,
and then we would discuss with the council before any of the rates of anything that
it is.
So it sounds like maybe the last time this was brought up, when you said you did a portion
of it, it feels like maybe that looks like that, this time too, maybe we just did our
electric increase, we just did our, you mentioned a couple of different increases we did.
Is it that they felt the same way then, so they, the electric was like, they presented
it on the electric, and they just went, we had a much of progress we wanted to do on the electric
side, the new sub-stations, stuff like that, they voted right then to do the rating increases
for the next five years.
The water was a little more steep water, it's a little more steep, because we had a lot, I mean,
obviously, our infrastructure on what I was doing very, very well.
I guess my question was, how long ago was the rate steady down?
The contract was in 2016 and executed over 17 and 18, when it was put in place.
And then they actually performed a 10-year study, but the council really approved the first five
years of the plan, and after reviewing the plan and talking with many others we think it's
worth doing another study, because enough has changed, our infrastructure has changed, our
project needs have changed, and that's what's taken into consideration whenever they do
the study is what our total cost is, what our cost to purchase the electric, and what our
cost is to deliver the electric throughout the city, and in any infrastructure upgrades we do,
and they have to create and set rates to project what our needs will be so that we don't over
recover or under recover.
So it's kind of like an actual study, an actual rate would do for insurance, you've got to figure
out exactly what your expenses are going to be, and then project out what you're going to recover
in rates, and then try to hit that bullseye out so that we recover appropriately to
cover our cost, but not over.
It's a pretty scientific rate study, they did a really good job, and the last one I've read at
multiple times, and that's what we're looking to repeat here to make sure that we all understand
the numbers and you need changes in that.
And I'm thinking that's kind of what I was asking it, we could see the previous rate study.
Oh yeah, it's just relatively available.
Okay.
Yeah.
Sorry, you wanted to see that before we approve this one?
I don't know.
How long do we got it on this?
Is it?
I mean, is it something that we really need to do something
in a table to the next meeting that way we don't have a look at it?
I feel like, yes, we say everybody,
if anybody, I can be looking at the Vigilia,
I mean, we can schedule a phone.
Yeah, I'd be happy to have you.
I'll sit down and talk to you.
I didn't really talk about it.
Sorry about it, you'll be able to table that.
Yes.
I mean, I feel like we're going to say we're going to spend $60,000
on something we need to be educated on what we're spending.
Not saying I don't trust what you're saying,
but I'd like to see the numbers for myself to see what,
who are they preparing us to, what was the process?
So we need to make a motion, we need to table over this table.
There's a beautiful motion about staying with them.
I'll make a motion that we table it until our next council meeting,
until you all can bring up what we're asking for.
Second.
Don't fall.
Hi.
Davis.
Sonberg.
Hi.
He steps up.
Perfect.
Hi.
Thank you, yes.
13.
Next time, good day.
I'll strap and claim for GRDA Realizing.
So good.
I'll strap in the jewel.
No, is it a turning that we use a regular basis?
They are part of the team that has been providing some consulting services
to DWT during the realizing phase of the GRDA Realizing.
And this is a claim for services for their consulting services on those particular
issues.
Providing historical references, which is what they are really good at, is explaining the history
of where we've been.
And they've done a great job and very intimately involved and been at already with any meetings
or anything that we've needed them for in their historical perspective.
That being said, this is pursuant to a contract that's already in place to pay them for services
rendered for that contract.
7,000, 3,000 and 2,000.
Any concerns or questions for both on that?
Work contractually obligated.
We are.
We are due to a contract for these services and they provided the services.
Make a motion, we approve.
I will second.
Davis.
E-SET.
I.
Sunder.
Nate.
Parker.
I.
14 staff reports.
15.
You know, the new business is registered.
The posting of this agenda.
16.
Just the community announcements.
17.
Again.
Sunder.
Second.
E-SET.
I.
Sunder.
Davis.
Aye.